This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands　高く [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands high.
(Everybody now raise your hands)
Take hold, there's a brand new tomorrow.
掴め　Brand new tomorrow [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
風の中で　自分を知る　ずっと最高のDreamだろう
It's a beautiful eternal dream...
...where you learn about yourself.
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh raise up you can't stop
Oh, raise up your hands now.
If you think you're lucky just to be alive go for the highest stake in the gamble.
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on　迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission　同じ一生
Same mission creates similar lives.
But your passion for your dream will make a difference.
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
You can never use the escalator.
Escalator　無しの永遠
But you can build up your strength, yeah yeah.
足腰鍛え　Let's begin yeah
You must eventually climb the stairs.
どうせのぼる階段
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Customize them the way you like.
Intense days go by.
削られて　過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Intense days go by. (But you know?)
攻めがいのあるGameと　笑い飛ばして
Just laugh it off, 'cause it's a game worth competing.
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands　ずっと [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands forever.
(Everybody now raise your hands up)
Run, sleepless challenger.
走れ　Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
今に生きる　理由を探す
It's a quest of the never-ending dream...
...where you now search for the reason to live.
夢尽きないQuest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
これは現実だ
This is reality.
明らかにペースアップしてる
The pace has definitely increased.
俺はガキになりきれてないんじゃねーのか
Can't I become childish enough ?
がむしゃらに攻めきれてないんじゃねーのか
Can't I push myself recklessly ?
ミスをしないとか
Trying not to make any mistakes
while conserving my tires...
二本目を考えてタイヤを温存するとか
Is that kind of calculating
making me drive like an old man ?
そういう計算が俺にジジくせー走りをさせてんじゃないのか
Ridiculous.
冗談じゃねー
I race with the faith that I'm the fastest out there.
俺は誰よりも速いと信じて
レースをやってるんだ
ぶつけた ガードレールに
He hit the guard rail !
何を起こってる
What's happening ?
レーシングドライバーが素人のハチロク相手に
A real racing driver is seriously
attacking an amateur Eight-Six driver !
本気で勝負にいってるよ
何だそれ ありえねぇ
What the hell ? That's impossible.
おお
Cleared the corner !
曲がったー
やっぱプロはすげー
Pros are amazing, after all. That was my limit.
俺は余裕なかった
あれ以上は突っ込めない
I couldn't have turned any faster.
正方向でバトルしてたら分が悪いってことか
So a traditional racing strategy
puts me at a disadvantage.
藤原が追い上げられてる
Fujiwara is being pushed hard.
いよいよ最終局面か
The final stage is near.
このバトルに勝つには
I've got to become childish
in order to win this battle.
ガキに成りきらなきゃダメなんだ
Fujiwara Zone
なー 藤原 お前はいつまで
Hey, Fujiwara, how much longer are you going
to make your son play such a meaningless game ?
自分の息子にあんな無意味なことをさせておくつもりなんだ
随分な言草だな
Look who's talking.
自分だって若い頃は散々公道で暴れてたくせに
You used to be a wild street
racer when you were young.
あの頃とは時代が違うんだ
Times have changed.
サーキットを走らなきゃ始まらんぞ
It's meaningless unless you drive on the circuit.
No matter how much practice he gains in mountain
passes, he won't advance past a certain level.
いくら峠で鍛えてもある程度から上のレベルにはいけない
お前の息子には才能がある
Your son is talented.
I'm telling you this because
I don't want you to waste it.
勿体無いと思うから言うんだ
こうなると苦しいよな
This is tough.
I feel like he's cornered.
逆に追い詰められた気分だよ
いや あいつはお前が考えているよりもずっと進化しているんだぜ
No, he's grown a lot more
than you realize, Fumihiro.
史浩
Is that so ?
そうなのか
先行になった場合は一本目から勝負に行く作戦だった
Since he's the leader, our strategy
is to finish the race on the first run.
細かい指示は昨日の時点で藤原に伝えてある
I already gave detailed
instructions to Fujiwara yesterday.
本当の仕掛けはこの先にあるのさ
The actual trick lies ahead.
えー
あいつの集中力は切れていないはずだ
There's no way he's lost
his concentration yet.
峠を越えるとか越えないとか
I don't understand what you mean by
growing out of the mountain passes or not.
そんな言葉の意味が俺には分からないね
なら 断言してもいいぞ
Then I can affirm to you that my
son will definitely win this time.
今度ばかりは100%こっちの勝ちだ
言っとくけど 勝負事に絶対はないんだぞ
Let me tell you, nothing can
be that certain in a competition.
涼介さんの読みが的確に来てる
Ryosuke's prediction was dead on.
I've got to focus.
ここは集中だ
イチかバチかやってみるしかないな
It's risky, but I've gotta try this.
車をコントロールする懐の深さこそが
His unlimited vehicle control skills
are the best part of the Fujiwara Zone.
藤原ゾーンの真骨頂なんだ
When he drives the Eight-Six, he creates
a situation that even a pro can't surpass.
あいつがハチロクという車を操る時
プロでも追従できない領域が存在する
That's the idea behind our trap, but I'm
sure our opponent has already figured it out.
それにかけたトラップのつもりだったが
こっちの狙いは今頃相手にも読まれているだろう
えー それじゃ 作戦は成功しないってことなのか
Do you mean our strategy will fail ?
いや 違う
No, it doesn't.
Do you think a pro would run
away from a clash of skills ?
技術の勝負をプロが逃げると思うか
プライドに賭けても 真正面から受けて立つはずだ
His pride will make him
face the challenge head on.
少なくとも今日の相手はそんな男だ
At the very least, today's opponent is that type.
コイントスでポジションを決めたがる程
I approved this strategy because
I thought an honest and fair person...
一本気でまっすぐな相手なら
見え見えのトラップに敢えて勝負をしてくると読んでのゴーサインさ
...who chooses their position with a coin
toss, will knowingly fall into our trap.
ましてや舞台は峠 あいつは峠の職人だからな
On top of that, they're
racing in a mountain pass.
My son is a master of it.
ゴールは近い
The goal is close.
It's going to be an over-the-limit braking
match at the entrance of the next corner.
限界を超えたオーバースピードでの突っ込み勝負
これこそ峠の勝負だよな
This is what mountain
pass racing is all about.
そのスピードでお前がクリアできるのなら
If you can clear the corner at that speed,
I should be able to, as well.
俺にだってできねぇはずがねー
受けて立ってやらー
I'll take your challenge !
The combined performance
of Fujiwara and the Eight-Six...
藤原とハチロクのパフォーマンスは
...can make them clear a corner at a
speed that pros would think impossible.
プロが曲がりきれないと判断するスピードからでも曲がれてしまう
そんなことが現実に起こりうる
Such things happen in reality.
全てをひっくるめての藤原ゾーンなんだ
It's all part of the Fujiwara Zone.
同じ速度で同じラインで
Same speed, same line...
しかもこっちはFRよりも限界の高いMRなんだ
Plus, my car's MR layout has
a higher limit than an FR's !
冗談だろう
This can't be happening !
負けたよ
I lost.
何を言っても言い訳になっちまうだろうが
Anything I say will sound like an excuse.
My car's got a mid-engine and rear wing.
こっちはミッドエンジンだし ウィーングもある
フルブレーキングなら絶対負けないと思ってたんだが
I thought I couldn't
lose during full braking.
あんな状況になる半歩手前でコントロールするのがプロなんだ
Pros are trained to control the car a
half step before such a situation occurs.
それでもお前は最後までコントロールしきったし
But you kept controlling your car
until the end, while I chickened out.
俺は逃げちまった
あれは逃げのスピンだ
The spin was caused by me backing away.
That's what I regret the most.
俺が一番悔やんでるのはそのことさ
あのまま突っ張ていれば クリアできたのか
If I had kept going, I don't know whether
I would have cleared the corner or hit a tree.
或いは立木に激突する羽目になっていたのか
それは分からないけど
My fighting spirit was defeated
by the fear of going off the course.
コースアウトの恐怖感に俺の闘争心が負けたんだ
同時に俺はお前に負けた
At the same time,
I was defeated by you.
俺はお前をサーキットの世界に誘うつもりでいたけど
I was going to invite you to
the world of circuit racing...
戦ってみてちょっと気が変わったよ
...but I've changed my mind after racing you.
お前独特の感覚がこっちの世界に来ても生かせないだろう
Your peculiar driving sense won't
have much use in my world.
それが何だか勿体無いような気がするんだ
I just feel like it'd be a waste.
お前はそっちの世界で極めてみろ
Be the best in your field.
You'll become one of a kind.
唯一無二の存在になれるはずだ
これは俺からのアドバイスだ
That's my advice to you.
ありがとうございました
Thank you.
おっ 待ってろよ 勝利の連絡だ
Oh, hold on.
A victory report has come.
もしもし 俺だ
Hello, it's me.
何 そっ そんな バカな
What the...?!
That's impossible !
そうか 拓海の奴 勝っちまったか
So Takumi won, huh ?
そんなことあるはずが ああ くそ
It couldn't have happened, dammit !
たかが峠の追いかけっこじゃねかよ
It's only a game of playing
tag in a mountain pass.
気休めはよせ お前に俺の悔しさが分かったたまるか
I don't need your comforting words !
You can't understand my frustration !
皆川だ
I'm Minagawa.
I'm Takahashi Keisuke.
俺は高橋啓介
I've heard that you're fast,
with consecutive wins against 4WD cars.
お前 速いんだってな
4WD相手に連勝中だそうだが
俺から逃げられたら大した者だ
If you can shake me off,
you are indeed something.
Let me see your proud sprint dash.
見せてもらおうか 自慢のスプリント
俺に先行しろって事か
Are you telling me to be the lead ?
了解だ あんた俺について来られるかい
Alright, but do you think
you can keep up with me ?
フン ほざいてろ
Shut the hell up.
なっ 健太
Listen, Kenta...
はい
Yes ?
This battle has a special meaning to me.
このバトル 俺には特別な意味があるんだ 分かるか
Do you understand ?
分かってますよ 俺
I do.
Watch me.
I'll win no matter what.
見てな 絶対勝つからな
拓海の奴どうなったのかな
I wonder how Takumi's race went.
電話ぐらいよこしたっていいのに
He should give us a call.
そういうとこ あいつ本当抜けてますよね
He's dense when it
comes to things like this.
He doesn't understand our concern.
こっちの心配も知らないで
まぁ ここで焦っても仕方がねぇよ
Yeah, but it's pointless to get frustrated.
拓海もそうだけどさ
Not just Takumi, but Takahashi Keisuke's
also going up against a pro racer, right ?
高橋啓介の相手もプロのドライバーだろう
ああ どっちも気が抜けねえよな
Right. Neither Takumi nor Takahashi
Keisuke can let their guard down.
拓海も 高橋啓介も
くー なんか興奮してきたぞ 俺
Geez, I'm so pumped up !
Five seconds till start !
スタート五秒前
Three...
三
Two...
二
One...
一
Go !
ゴー
妙にイライラするというか
Why do I feel so irritated,
or is it more like vicious ?
残酷な気分になっていくのはなぜかな
完膚なきまでに叩きのめしてやりたい気分だ
I want a complete victory over you.
俺にはわかる
I know what Keisuke means by special.
啓介さんが特別だと言った意味が
It's because his opponent today is a pro.
それは今日の相手がプロだという事なんだ
He's trying to test his skills against a pro.
プロを相手に自分の技術が
どこまで通用するのかを試そうとしているんだ
No matter how many amateur
4WD drivers you've defeated...
素人の4WDにどれだけ勝てた所で
所詮素人には車の限界を引き出せない
...amateurs can't use the
full potential of their cars.
タイヤの状態が一番いい所でスパートを掛ければ
If I dash when the tires
are in their best condition...
ガタイの重いこの８０スープラでも余裕でかわせる
...I should be able to overtake
you even with my heavy 80 Supra.
同じFR同士のこのバトル
The battle between rear-wheel-drive cars boils
down to the game of conserving the rear tires.
リアタイヤの消耗戦に尽きる
本当のタイヤマネージメントは
You can't attain real tire management skills
unless you take part in professional racing.
レースというフィールドに身を置いた者でなきゃ
絶対に身に付かない
You'll wear out your rear tires
by trying too hard in the first run.
一本目で精々頑張ってリアタイヤを終わらせるこったら
スピードが自慢の峠の兄ちゃんはそこでお仕舞いだろう
Then the proud speed brat of the
mountain passes will be finished.
な　覚えてるか
Hey, do you remember...
あれは確か　栃木での東堂塾戦での第二ラウンドだった
...the second round of the battle
against the Todo School in Tochigi ?
上りと下りの混合ステージで
In that complex stage
of uphill and downhill...
...everyone thought you'd choose Keisuke's FD
against the racing driver, Tachi Tomoyuki.
レーシングドライバーの舘智幸の相手として
てっきり啓介のFDでいくものとばかり皆は思っていた
けど　お前が指名したのは　藤原のハチロクだったよな
But you chose Fujiwara's Eight-Six.
あのときの説明があまり印象的で
Your explanation was so
sensational that I couldn't forget.
忘れられないんだ
異なる二種類のアプローチで
You said you're using two approaches in your
pursuit of the fastest record in street racing.
公道最速を目指している
プロジェクトDに二人のドライバーがいるのはそのためだって
That's why there are two drivers in Project D.
そのことか
Oh, that.
I amazed you remember that.
よく覚えていたな
忘れやしないさ
Of course I did.
It sounded so meaningful.
凄く重い 意味のあることだからな
藤原は　峠に特化したスペシャリストで
Fujiwara is a peculiar type, who
specializes in mountain passes.
ある意味　変則派
それは正しくそのとおりになっていると思う
And I think he's become
exactly as you described.
一方　啓介の方は
On the other hand, Keisuke is a traditional type,
who adapts racing techniques to the street.
モータースポーツの技術を峠に応用していく
正統派スタイルだと
同じ正統派同士なら
You chose Fujiwara because we wouldn't have stood
a chance against a pro in a clash of traditional skills.
プロ相手に勝ち目はない
そのための藤原の起用だったと
確かに　そう言ったな
I did say that.
だったら　今日のバトルはどうなるんだ
Then what'll happen during today's battle ?
今日の相手はそれこそトップレベルの正統派なんだぞ
Today's opponent has top level traditional skills.
ダウンヒルはハチロクの方やら勝ちましたが
The Eight-Six kid won the downhill battle,
but I wonder how the hill climb round will develop.
ヒルクライムはどうなりますかな
This time I want to
hear your prediction, Hojo.
今度は北条はんの予想を聞かせてもらいたいですな
Minagawa is a proud person, so he
doesn't think he can lose to an amateur.
皆川という男は自信家だから
素人相手に負けるとは思っちゃいない
だけど　奴が考えているより高橋弟はいいドライバーだ
But the younger Takahashi is a
better driver than Minagawa thinks.
アクセルワークに特化してよく鍛えられている
He's well trained, especially his acceleration work.
あのFDがここまで負けなしで来られているのは
That's why that FD's been undefeated so far.
そのせいだからな
なるほど
I see.
それに　後ろにいるのはあの涼介だ
Plus, he's backed by Ryosuke.
あの男が勝ち目のないバトルに
I don't think he'd send his brother
into a race without a strategy.
無策で弟を送る出してくるとは考え難い
同感ですな
I feel the same way.
絶対にもつれる
This battle will be tangled up. It's a big
mistake to think Minagawa will win easily.
皆川が楽に勝ってると思ったら
大間違いだぜ
どっちの味方ですかな　北条はん
Whose side are you on, Hojo ?
過去にどんな因縁があったんでっか
What happened between you and
our opponent's leader in the past ?
向こうのリーダと
そんな大げさのものは俺と涼介の間にはないよ
There's nothing important
between Ryosuke and I.
涼介と因縁あるのは　俺の兄貴だ
It's my older brother who has a
bitter connection to Ryosuke.
死神と呼ばれたドライバーでっか
The driver who's nicknamed the Grim Reaper ?
先行がFD
The FD is the lead ? Minagawa
must have chosen to be the chaser.
皆川め　後ろ選んだか
一本目のこのポジションが
Their positions in the first round will be the key to the outcome of this race.
勝敗そのものを決するカギになる
やっぱ馬力では負けてるな
As expected, he's got more horsepower.
But that doesn't mean much in this battle.
だけど　このバトルではそんなことはあまり意味はない
Both of us are well aware of that.
お互いにいやというほど分かっていることだ
確かに　今回の相手は超一流の正統派だろうな
Indeed, our opponent is a
top-class traditional driver.
コンペティションで鍛え抜かれた技術に隙はない
With competition-trained skills,
he won't show any weakness.
タイムを削りとる時計のセンス
The sense of shaving time off,
mental ease at the limit, and stamina...
限界領域での精神的な余裕
それにスタミナ
どれをとっても　公道の走り屋が辿り着けるレベルにはない
None of them can be
attained by street racers.
It'd be the right strategy for us to throw
a change-up, instead of a fast ball...
直球勝負ではなく　チェンジアップで交わしにいくのが正解だろうか
啓介には　そんな選択肢はないからな
...but we don't have that kind of choice with Keisuke.
But I've sent Keisuke out with confidence...
それでも俺は　自信を持って啓介を送り出している
なぜなら
...because Keisuke has grown.
今の啓介は成長しているんだ
スペシャルメニュー
Special menu ? Like a boot camp ?
つまりは特訓ってこと
Right.
そうだ
後輪駆動のFD3Sで強力な４WDを相手に勝ち抜いていくことは至難の業だ
It will be extremely difficult to continue defeating
powerful 4WD cars with your rear-wheel-drive FD3S.
重要なのは　どれだけ効率よくタイヤを使えるかということだろう
The key is how effectively
you use the rear tires.
これは　そのための練習なんだ
This training is for that.
一日5往復でいい
Just five round trips
a day should be fine.
Try to match the times I've set for the
ten laps of uphill and downhill driving.
上りと下りの十本のタイムを
なるべく誤差なく　俺が設定したタイムに揃える
これを全てノートに記録して
Write every time down in this notebook,
and show it to me every day.
毎日俺に見せること
設定したタイムと大きく誤差が出たら
If there's a noticeable gap between my preset time and
your actual time, try to figure out why, and report in detail.
理由を自分で考えて
なるべく具体的にレポートしておくこと
それだけだ
That's all.
Fine by me, but these times are quite
a bit slower than Akagi's best record.
それはいいけど
兄貴の設定したこのタイム
赤城道路のレコードタイムにはほどとおいっていうか
こんなの簡単すぎねーか
Don't you think this is too easy ?
クリアすればいいとは言ってないぜ
I didn't say you have to surpass those times.
It's not good to be faster or slower.
速すぎても遅すぎてもNGなんだ
ええ
What ?
上りでも下りでも
Whether it's uphill or downhill,
in rain, or behind a slower car...
雨が降っていても
遅い車に捕まった時でも
...you must aim for one fixed time.
例外なく目指すタイムは一つだ
楽だと思ったら大間違いだぜ
If you think it's easy,
you're seriously mistaken.
どれだけ難しいかすぐに分かる
You'll know how hard it is soon enough.
If you're frustrated that you weren't chosen for
the race against Tachi Tomoyuki in Tochigi...
栃木で舘智幸の相手に指名されなかったことが悔しいなら
...complete this menu every day until fall.
このメニューを秋まで毎日続けてみろ
それが神奈川まで勝ち抜くための
That's an absolute necessity for you to
continue winning until the Kanagawa races.
絶対条件だ
そうだったのか
I see. I didn't know Keisuke had
to put in that kind of training.
啓介がそんな練習をしていたとは知らなかった
So the second race against Todo
School must have made you do that.
やっぱり　きっかけは東堂塾との第二戦だったんだな
でも　それはどんな意味を持つ特訓なんだ
But what's the meaning
behind the special training ?
That training was slightly modified for Keisuke...
あの練習は　いくらかは啓介用に改良してあるが
...but it's basically the same menu
I used when I was younger.
基本的には俺が昔　自分でやってきたメニューと同じだ
涼介と同じ
The same menu ?
闇雲に全開で走り込みをするだけなら
If you drive blindly at full throttle, you'll only put
stress on the car, and your skills won't improve.
車に負担がかかるだけで
技術の進歩は望めない
Drive at the limit over and over, and
your times will eventually even out.
限界に近いペースで走っていれば
タイムは自然と揃っていくものだ
中途半端に抑えてタイムを揃えるほうが難しい
It's more difficult to get a set time while holding back,
because your times can easily be faster or slower.
上にも下にも誤差が出てしまう
Just flooring the gas pedal won't work.
だた気合で踏み込むだけのアクセルワークでは通用しない
理性的に　開度をコントロールする技術が必要になっていく
You must learn the technique of
controlling the throttle precisely.
それだけじゃないぜ
That's not all.
In rain, you have to be creative in setting the pace for
the constantly-changing friction coefficient of the surface.
雨が降れば　刻々と変化する路面のミューに対応したペース作りを
工夫しなければいけないし
遅い車に追いついてしまった時の対応も
It's difficult to cope with the situation
when you get stuck behind a slow car.
また大変なんだ
Suppose you lost 4 seconds until the overtake
point, you must recover exactly 4 seconds.
追い抜くまで四秒をロスしたとすれば
その四秒を精確にリカバーしなければ行かない
ストップウォッチを見ないで
And you do that with the internal clock in
your body, instead of relying on a stopwatch.
体の中の感覚だけでそれをやる
そんなこと　できるものなのか
Is that possible ?
すぐにはできない
Not right away, but you'll be able to,
depending on how you train yourself.
だけど　トレーニング次第ではできるようになるんだ
That's the traditional way of driving practice.
走りこみというのは　本来そういうものだ
単調な練習の積み重ねの中で
You attain an abundance of information
through repetitious simple training.
膨大な量のデータを体の中に蓄積していき
タイムの変動に敏感なセンサーが養われていくんだ
And then your internal sensor
will become sensitive to time.
アクセルペダルの踏み加減を細かくわけてコントロールするんだ
I've gotta control the gas pedal
depression in a number of small steps.
スピードを思いどおりコントロールすることは
It's much harder to control your desired
speed than to try to drive as fast as possible.
精一杯早く走るより　ずっと難しい
啓介の凄いところはやると決めたら
The great thing about Keisuke is that once he sets his
mind to it, he'll finish a task without any compromise.
トコトン妥協せずにやりぬくところだろう
He drives every day,
except for Project D's race days.
プロジェクトDの遠征の日以外は
毎日欠かさず走っているんだ
毎日か
Every day ?!
走りこんで　自分の感覚と実際のタイムとのズレが修正されていくに連れて
As the gap between the desired
and actual times narrowed...
...he began to understand what
made his time too fast or too slow.
何がタイムを悪くし　何がタイムを良くするのかが
理解できるようになって行くし
レポートすることによって常に分析することが習慣になってくれば
The daily report made him create
a habit of analyzing things rationally...
感覚重視だった啓介の走りに
...which added a logical foundation
to his intuitive driving style.
理論の裏付けが構築されていくんだ
He must be aware of an unexpected
side effect of the training, as well.
だぶんあいつはもう気がついているだろう
あの練習が齎してくれる意外な副産物に
兄貴は特訓をアクセルワークのためのものだと言っていた
Brother told me the special training
was for my accelerator work.
But that's not exactly true.
だけど　本当は違う気がする
この激戦区の神奈川エリアを勝ち抜くために
There's something else I need, in order to
continue winning in this tough Kanagawa area.
それは絶対に必要なものだ
見てろよ兄貴　やっと俺は分かってきたぜ
Watch me, Brother.
I've come to realize what it is.
神奈川の初戦を思い出してみろ　史浩
Remember our first battle in Kanagawa, Fumihiro ?
チーム246のランエボか
The Lan Evo of Team 246 ?
Keisuke accelerated in the mid-section and won.
中盤すぎに一気にスパートをかけて振り切って勝った
His tire management in the
second half was splendid...
前半のタイヤを温存するマネージメントも鮮やかだったが
ここ一発のスプリントに磨きがかかっていることのほうに
...but I'm more interested in his
refined acceleration when needed.
俺は注目している
Speed is what I meant by a side effect.
俺が言う副産物というのはつまり
スピードなんだ
峠に特化したタイヤマネージメントと時計のセンス
Tire management skills specialized for
mountain passes, and sense of time...
その二つを高いレベルで身につけさせることが
The real reason I made Keisuke train that way was
to make him attain those two skills at a high level.
あの練習を啓介にさせている本来の狙いだ
だけど　不思議なことに
Strangely enough, the menu
was designed to slow him down...
メニューそのものは速さを抑えて走る練習であるにも関わらず
...but it helped him drive
a lot faster in the end.
結果的に飛び切りの速さを身につけるということになってしまう
And today's strategy is to make
the best use of that side effect.
そして今日のバトルにはその副産物を全面に押し出して戦う作戦だ
つ　つまり
In other words, Keisuke will engage in a head to
head fight against a racing driver in a sprint battle ?
レーシングドライバーを相手に
ガチンコのスプリント勝負で行くってのか
藤原ばかりに　いいところは持っていかせねーからな
I won't let Fujiwara steal the show.
関東最強最速　プロジェクトDの伝説は俺が作る
I'll build the legend of Project D,
the best of the Kanto area.
Not too shabby.
こしゃくだな
コーナー脱出時のアクセル開度を
He's trying to catch me off guard by altering
the throttle opening at the exit of every corner.
毎回少しずつ変えながら俺を牽制してやがる
85から90パーセントくらいの間をランダムに移動しつつ
Opening the throttle randomly between 85-90%, he's
gauging vehicle distance to decide when to accelerate.
車間も計りながら
飛び出すタイミングを探っていやがるのが
これだけの芸当ができるやつとはな
I didn't expect him to pull off such a trick.
He's much better than I thought.
俺が考えていたよりもこいつはうまい
ヒルクライムもそろそろ中盤に差し掛かるころかな
The first half of the hill climb battle is almost over.
What did you think of our
opponent this time around ?
藤原から見て　今回の相手はどうなんだ
実際に戦ってみた感触は
What's your actual impression ?
速いということにかけては本当に速いと思うな
When it comes to speed,
race car drivers are really fast.
レースをやる人たちは
俺のときは一旦は引き離すことには成功したんですよ
In my race, I was able to pull away once.
このまま逃げるしかないと思って
I put on a spurt at 100%, believing that
I must outrun my opponent from there...
本当に必死に百パーセントのスパートをかけたんだけど
...but I was caught, and felt pressured.
逆に追い付かれて追い詰められて
滅茶苦茶動揺しますよ
I panic when I lose
in speed at a critical moment.
ここぞいうところでスピード負けするのは
ま　そうだろうな
I understand that.
だけど　啓介さんは俺とは違う気がする
But Keisuke is different from me.
なんっていうのかな
How do I put it...?
このごろ啓介さんは雰囲気が出てるんですよ
Keisuke has an aura....
...which makes me glad that he's on my side,
because I don't want to race against him.
この人と勝負するのは嫌だな
味方でよかったなっていう
速い相手は一杯いるけれど　啓介さんと勝負するほうが
There are many fast drivers, but
I believe it'd be tough to fight Keisuke.
きついんじゃないかって
始まったか
It's begun.
任せたぞ　啓介
I'm counting on you, Keisuke.
俺のチームに二人の天才が揃ってくれない限り
Without two genius drivers on my team, it'll be
impossible to sweep all the races in Kanagawa.
神奈川エリアの全勝は無理だ
プロジェクトDの完成もないんだぜ
And Project D won't be complete.
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Takahashi Keisuke:
Kogashiwa Kai:
Fujiwara Bunta:
Kogashiwa Ken:
Minagawa Hideo:
Kubo Eiji:
Hojo Gou:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Seki Tomokazu
Kanna Nobutoshi
Ishizuka Unsho
Arimoto Tetsuya
Konishi Katsuyuki
Kase Yasuyuki
Kiuchi Hidenobu
Iketani Koichiro:
Kenji:
Takeuchi Itsuki:
Matsumoto:
Fumihiro:
Kenta:
Yao Kazuki
Takagi Wataru
Iwata Mitsuo
Nishi Ryotaro
Hosoi Hajime
Okano Kosuke
Following the brake light of the front car.
Falling perfect lighten the focal
A shimmering light up ahead in the dark street.
暗い道の先にぼんやりにじむ明かり
It's the silence like a silent film.
If the tires strike a silent wind
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Lillian-Hime
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
Steve S.
The light was all I could depend on.
頼りになるものはそれしか見えなかった
この並木道を抜けていけばきっと
I felt like I could catch it...
...if I passed through this tree-lined street.
つかめるような気がした
Give up! I just can't understand
Get up! I just can't understand.
I couldn't find what I'd been looking for.
外にはまだ捜し物は何もなくて
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
At this place.
この場所から
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf
I lost my way.
I lost my way
白く曇った窓と的外れなNavigation
Fogged up windows, and...
...messed up navigation.
赤く変わった信号で
As the stoplight turns red...
サイドミラーに映る視界を遮るLight
...a light in the side mirror blinds my eyes.
冷たい風が入り込まないように
I gradually close the window...
窓をそっと締めたんだ
...to stop the cold wind from blowing in.
Get up! I just can't understand.
Give up! I just can't understand
そこに広がる道を選んで進む僕は
We must choose one of the paths that lie ahead.
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
Because you're with me.
君がいるなら
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf